[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
Let's take a final minute to summarize what we have seen in today's module.
لنستغل الدقيقة الأخيرة في تلخيص ما رأيناه في وحدة اليوم.
Around scaling to large datasets and online learning.
حول تحجيم مجموعات البيانات الكبيرة والتعلم عبر الإنترنت.
Now, we use gradient to scale to large datasets, but
والآن، من المعروف أننا نستخدم معامل التدرج لتحجيم مجموعات البيانات الكبيرة،
this is not the only approach that's used.
ولكن هذا ليس نهج الاستخدام الوحيد.
In fact, a lot of scaling that we do is about dealing with multicore processors.
إن العديد من عمليات التحجيم التي نقوم بها هي في الواقع حول التعامل مع المعالجات متعددة النواة.
So, the fact that processors have multiple cores and it can do parallel computation.
لذا، فالحقيقة أن المعالجات لديها أنوية متعددة ويمكنها القيام بعمليات حسابية متوازية.
And then, using large computers clusters with 10 of machines, 100 machines,
وبعد ذلك، استخدام مجموعات كبيرة من أجهزة الكمبيوتر تتراوح بين 10 أجهزة أو 100 جهاز،
1,000 machines, 100,000 machines, and so on.
أو 1000 جهاز أو 100000 جهاز وهكذا.
And this requires new kinds of machinery algorithms which are called distributed
وهذا يتطلب نوع جديد من الخوارزميات الآلية والتي تدعى
and parallel algorithms that can be spread out over a thousand machine.
الخوارزميات الموزعة والمتوازية التي يمكنها الانتشار عبر أكثر من ألف جهاز.
It's a very important topic.
وهذا موضوع مهم للغاية.
It's actually what a lot of my personal research is about.
وهو في الواقع ما تدور حوله الكثير من أبحاثي الشخصية.
How do you do this written machine or any algorithms, unfortunately is not something
وهو كيفية القيام بتلك الخوارزميات الآلية المكتوبة، ولكن لسوء الحظ ذلك ليس بالأمر
that are not going to have time to cover in the current course.
الذي لدينا الوقت الكافي لتناوله في هذه الدورة الحالية.
As a summary we seen that a small modification of your gradient
وكملخص، فقد رأينا أن القيام بتعديل بسيط في معامل تدرج الخوارزمية
algorithm can incredible improvement in the overall running time of the approach,
يمكنه أن يحسن بشكل مذهل في وقت التشغيل الكلي للنهج،
and that makes a huge difference in practice.
وذلك يحدث اختلاف كبير في الممارسة.
The many practical challenges associated in gradient is extremely useful.
حيث تعد العديد من التحديات العملية المرتبطة بمعامل التدرج مفيدة للغاية.
And the same kind of techniques that we saw here can also be used for
ويمكن استخدام نفس الأساليب التي رأيناها هنا أيضًا في التعلم عبر الإنترنت.
online learning which is a whole different type of machine learning which
والذي يعتبر نوعًا مختلفًا كليًا من التعلم الآلي
is also of great practical significance.
وهو أيضًا ذو أهمية علمية كبيرة.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]